# questions stored in dictionary
# list > each item is dictionary > "options" key in dict has value of list

computer_science_questions = [
    {
        "question": "What does OOP stand for in programming?\n",
        "options": [
            "A) Object-Oriented Programming\n"
            " (B) Object-Oriented Protocol\n"
            " (C) Object-Operational Programming\n"
            " (D) Object-Oriented Process"
        ],
        "answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which programming language is primarily used for web development?\n",
        "options": [
            "A) Python\n"
            " (B) C++\n"
            " (C) JavaScript\n"
            " (D) Java"
        ],
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does API stand for?\n",
        "options": [
            "A) Application Programming Interface\n"
            " (B) Automated Protocol Interface\n"
            " (C) Advanced Programming Interface\n"
            " (D) Application Protocol Integration"
        ],
        "answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does SDLC stand for?\n",
        "options": [
            "A) Systematic Data Lifecycle Cycle\n"
            " (B) Software Development Lifecycle\n"
            " (C) System Design and Logic Cycle\n"
            " (D) Software Debugging Lifecycle"
        ],
        "answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which SDLC model is also known as the linear-sequential model?\n",
        "options": [
            "A) Big Bang Model\n"
            " (B) Spiral Model\n"
            " (C) Waterfall Model\n"
            " (D) Iteration Model"
        ],
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a phase in the Waterfall model of SDLC?\n",
        "options": [
            "A) Requirement Analysis\n"
            " (B) Design\n"
            " (C) Iteration\n"
            " (D) Testing"
        ],
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct way to declare a variable in Python?\n",
        "options": [
            "A) variable = 5;\n"
            " (B) int variable = 5;\n"
            " (C) variable : 5;\n"
            " (D) variable = 5"
        ],
        "answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a valid data type in Python?\n",
        "options": [
            "A) String\n"
            " (B) Float\n"
            " (C) Char\n"
            " (D) List"
        ],
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which keyword is used to define a function in Python?\n",
        "options": [
            "A) func\n"
            " (B) define\n"
            " (C) function\n"
            " (D) def"
        ],
        "answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will 3 * 'abc' evaluate to in Python?\n",
        "options": [
            "A) 9\n"
            " (B) abcabcabcabc\n"
            " (C) ['abc', 'abc', 'abc']\n"
            " (D) abcabcabc"
        ],
        "answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "question": "What will the following code snippet output?\n\nmy_list = [1, 2, 3, 4, 5]\nprint(my_list[1:4])\n",
        "options": [
            "A) [1, 2, 3]\n"
            " (B) [2, 3, 4]\n"
            " (C) [2, 3]\n"
            " (D) [1, 3, 4]"
        ],
        "answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the primary goal of the deployment phase in SDLC?\n",
        "options": [
            "A) To start development of the software\n"
            " (B) To design the system architecture\n"
            " (C) To release the software to the users\n"
            " (D) To fix bugs and enhance the software"
        ],
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a UML class diagram, how is a parent-child relationship between classes represented?\n",
        "options": [
            "A) A dashed line with a closed arrowhead pointing to the parent class\n"
            " (B) A solid line with an open arrowhead pointing to the child class\n"
            " (C) A solid line with a closed arrowhead pointing to the parent class\n"
            " (D) A dashed line with an open arrowhead pointing to the child class"
        ],
        "answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the acronym UML stand for in software engineering and design?\n",
        "options": [
            "A) Unified Methodology Language\n"
            " (B) Unified Modeling Logic\n"
            " (C) Unified Model Language\n"
            " (D) Unified Modeling Language"
        ],
        "answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which SDLC model is often considered less structured, lacks detailed planning, and is best suited for smaller projects with less complexity?\n",
        "options": [
            "A) Waterfall Model\n"
            " (B) Iteration Model\n"
            " (C) Spiral Model\n"
            " (D) Big Bang Model"
        ],
        "answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which SDLC model emphasizes breaking down a project into smaller cycles, allowing for incremental development and continuous feedback?\n",
        "options": [
            "A) Big Bang Model\n"
            " (B) Waterfall Model\n"
            " (C) Iteration Model\n"
            " (D) V-Model"
        ],
        "answer": "C"
    },
        {
        "question": "What does IDE stand for?\n",
        "options": [
            "A) Idle Development Environment\n"
            " (B) Integrated Development Environment\n"
            " (C) Intelligent Development Environment\n"
            " (D) None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B"
    }
]